NYSUT Field Services Department Files. 6174/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Southern Tier Regional Office: Correspondence, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  History of Excellence In Teaching funds in Horseheads Central School District as it related to Horseheads School Services Association, May 9; memo to Jim Conti requesting speaker from PERB for Southern Tier Spring Conference of March 17; memo to Jim Conti re lack of usefulness to staff of monthly computer printouts re arbitrations, potential for great savings in discontinuing practice, November 14; policy statement adopted by NYSUT Board of Directors in 1974 re NYSUT locals and Landrum-Griffin Act; agenda for Southern Tier Regional Office (STRO) staff retreat of September 20-21; newspaper clippings re impact of teacher suspension for hitting students with ruler, questions of interpretation of rules on physical force and physical contact; memo form Jim Conti asking about stop/loss insurance, June 21; notes from negotiations session between Horseheads School Services Association and school district, June 4; memo to Jim Conti re Mt. Upton/Gilbertsville merger, June 6; memos re Webster Central School District case in Court of Appeals, re sub- contracting, May; memo from Corning-Painted Post school district re required training re recognizing and reporting child abuse, September 24; memo from Jim Conti re ineligibility for Social Security refund for teachers who had tax withheld while on sick leave, change in rules, statute of limitations, May 23; memo from Jim Conti noting that flexible spending accounts do not continue into retirement, May 22; memo to Jim Conti estimating an increase of 40 members, plus 40 new school-related personnel members with the addition of the Harpursville SRP local, in the Southern Tier Regional Office for 1990-91; memo re Horseheads Excellence In Teaching situation, May 10; 33-page document, "Union Organizing Update: The Employers Legal Response," January, with cover note to Jim Conti, "used by hospital management in Southern Tier," March 19; citation of court case, Rush-Henrietta Central School District v. Newman as chair of PERB, et al., re smoking regulations, with cover memo to Jim Conti, April 16; findings and recommendation of State Education Department hearing panel in 3020a charge against teacher in Charlotte Valley Central School District, February; citation of appeal of Lippman, et al. v. Board of Education of Sewanhaka Central High School District, et al., February; correspondence between Jim Conti and NYSUT field representative John Callahan discussing recent health care conference, reasons for rising health care costs, misguided cost containment proposals, February 2; question re ability to represent Cortland Nurses Association (registered nurses who had been released from the Cortland City School District CSEA bargaining unit and requested affiliation with NYSUT), January 11; memos re fee question for attorney presentation at Endicott Superintendent's Conference Day workshop, potential issue for NEA to exploit, January
- Suffolk: Meeting on Self Insurance, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  September 7th, 1990. Presentation by consulting actuaries Milliman & Robertson, Inc., A Self-Insured Employee Medical Benefit Program: Cost Projection and Comments, June 8; draft of East End Health Plan Trust Agreement (BOCES Suffolk County), with cover memo, October 2; list of steering committee members; Steering Committee Recommendations to School Boards and Participating Unions in Regard to the East End Health Insurance Consortium: Overall Purpose of Moving Is to Reduce the Tax Rate and Improve the Plan, revised August 24, with cover memo from Shelter Island Union Free School District re revisions, August 30; opinion letters from consultants and actuaries Martin E. Segal Company, July; related correspondence
- Jim Conti: Suffolk County Consolidation, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  School District Consolidation Report Findings and Recommendations; Objections and Answers, Next Steps, with cover memo summarizing report, December 20, 1989
- Suffolk Regional Office: Correspondence, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  Report by NYS Department of Labor of industrial hygiene investigation at Reed Jr. High School and Senior High School, Central Islip High School, July 19, 1988; follow-up letter to Department of Labor General Counsel from Central Islip Teachers Association, expressing frustration and disappointment at lack of compliance, May 24, 1989; request from regional office for additional secretarial help, August 28, 1990, with negative reply; correspondence between superintendent and attorney re conditions of retirement buyout of teachers at Bridgehampton school district, July; handwritten notes re East End (Health) Consortium, September 7; material data sheet re glue used for wallpaper at Suffolk Regional Office, with cover memo inquiring as to whether contents were hazardous, January 5; memo from Regional Director re possible retirement problem concerning Tier I and maternity, December 18; December regional report re negotiations and other activities; letter from Regional Director to factfinder protesting recommendation re Bayport-Blue point Union Free School District and Bayport-Blue Point Teachers Association health insurance negotiations, November 30; memo re Long Island Symposium on the Economy, July 3; letters re abolishing teacher and other staff positions at Port Jefferson school district, whether layoff of a teacher aide followed Civil Service rules, November-December; materials re East End Self-Insurance; Newsday clippings and editorial re rising administrative costs at Long Island schools, smaller student population, with cover memo re clouds on the horizon, July 18; list of school districts involved in self-funded health insurance discussions, July 9; memo re negotiations for successor agreement to 1989-90 Excellence In Teaching agreement at Middle County district, June 26; letter to State Insurance Commission re difficulty by employees of Montauk school district in finding chiropractors acceptable to Metropolitan Life Insurance (Empire Plan), need to drive 40 miles, May 15; memo re Long Island People for Learning training on PR techniques, May 15; memo re East Moriches smoking policy, possible ground for Improper Practice charge, May 9; memo re agency fee, Beck decision, March 28; letter to AFT president Al Shanker, wishing Jack Nugent, president of the International Association of Machinists, good luck in organizing St. John's Episcopal Hospital in Smithtown, whose technical employees had been represented by NYSUT/AFT, March 9; memo from Jim Conti re health and safety violations at Central Islip School District, March 6, related press release from Attorney General's office, newspaper clippings; request from Sayville Teachers Association for budget analysis of Sayville school district because of anticipation of layoffs, February; material safety data sheet from Pitney Bowes re print powder used in copy machine, request to NYSUT staff for analysis, January 16; memo referring to Suffolk County consolidation report (see previous folder), January 10
- Suffolk Regional Office: Misc., 1990 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  Report by Nassau-Suffolk School Boards Association, "Issues Facing Public Education on Long Island," March 1990
- Syracuse Regional Office: Correspondence, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  Meeting notice for Industrial Relations Research Association, Central New York Chapter, re health and safety in the workplace, for November 29; In-Service Plan for Presentation by the Teacher Evaluation Committee of the Model for Teacher Evaluation; memos from Jim Conti re Auburn Teachers Association request for NYSUT legal intervention challenging recently passed policy disallowing voting on labor contract matters by School Board members with relatives employed by the district, related materials, including petition to the Commissioner of Education, September-November; materials from state Attorney General's office re compliance with "Right-to-Know" Law by Onondaga-Cortland-Madison BOCES, April; memo to Jim Conti reporting on dissolution of FNHP (Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals) Syracuse Chapter, decline in membership since 1986 strike, legal and public relations implications, July 10; memo informing Jim Conti that the FNHP Syracuse chapter had officially gone out of business, October 3, with attached notice and remaining dues check; memo to NYSUT legal counsel re seniority/tenure/layoff matter in Oswego BOCES district, October 22; letter from state Department of Labor inviting application for funding for establishment of labor-management committees, September 28; contractual agreement between the Board of Education of the Syracuse City School District and the Syracuse Teachers Association, Inc., representing Unit 1, Teachers and Ancillary Services, effective January 1, 1988, to December 31, 1991; Commissioner of Education decision in application of a child with a handicapping condition, question of whether Committee on Special Education must provide skilled nursing to allow student to attend public school (appeal dismissed), June 11; review of document for teachers accused of misconduct, with suggested changes from Jim Conti, June 25; memo from Jim Conti re Benjamin-Rush contract remaining in force despite filing for decertification by employer, July 19; memo re "epidemic" of school budget defeats in central New York, with attached newspaper clippings, June 26; newspaper clipping re comparable worth efforts, June 3; request for legal opinion on various matters re Onondaga Community College Federation of Teachers, May- June; letter from NYSUT Regional Staff Director to state Department of Labor Hazard Abatement Board requesting full funding of the CNYCOSH Training and Education Program for 1990-91, February 13; materials re health and safety conditions at Onondaga-Cortland-Madison BOCES, March 7; letters from president of the North Syracuse Education Association, complaining about "discourteous arrogant and snide" manner in which her request for a legal consultation with NYSUT attorneys was refused, demanding refund of legal expenses for private law firm, January 5 and 9; reply from NYSUT executive director Jim Wood, January 26; memo to Jim Conti re approval to teach a course on contract bargaining at Cornell University's ILR School, December 21, 1989
- Training Director: Correspondence, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  Memos re arbitration and cross-examination training; NYSUT Workshop Cataloging data sheets; list of meetings and conferences; memo re train-the-trainer program in education reform/school restructuring, August 13; confidential memo offering position of NYSUT training director to Charles Caputo, March 5
- Utica Regional Office Correspondence, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  Report and recommendations of a State Education Department 3020a hearing panel in Rome City School District v. James Angelo, with cover memo from Jim Conti, February 12; letter from president of Mohawk Teachers Association complaining of lack of support from NYSUT Public Relations Department in helping with campaign for new building, January 19; reply from Regional Staff Director, urging working with field representative, February 14; materials, including medical report, of industrial arts teacher at New Hartford school district in pending OSHA case, October
- UUP Correspondence, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  Improper Practice charge with PERB against SUNY Health Science Center by CSEA, notice of conference for June 27; memo re PERB decision re Regents degree program, April 9; memo from NYSUT counsel Bernard Ashe re physicians' request for legal counsel, particular vulnerability to complaints to licensing authorities, June 22, with attached letter from chairman of the governing board of Clinical Practice Management Plan, Downstate Medical Center, April 20; letter from State Education Department to pharmacist at State University Hospital at Stonybrook, informing him that he was being investigated for professional misconduct and directing him to appear for an interview, February 14
- RSD Memos (1 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  List of locals in each regional office, with field representatives and potential; list of release time and compensation for local leaders, with cover memo advising that the process of gathering the information was tedious, suggesting better alternatives, January 24, 1989; related memos; Putnam/Westchester Counties Privileges of Bargaining Representatives 1987-88; booklet for young people, "What Is a Union?" by Althea, Rourke Enterprises, 1981; poster describing NYSUT leadership and regional offices, "Unparallel membership services in a times of change"; memo re decision of Administrative Law Judge re Ithaca Teachers Association distribution of Excellence In Teaching monies, November 30, 1989; text of keynote address of AFL-CIO President Lane Kirkland, 1989 AFL-CIO Convention, November 13, 1989; Bureau of National Affairs articles re agency shop fees limited in California, drug testing, collective bargaining for smoking policies; description of AFT training programs for Paraprofessional and School-Related Personnel (PSRP) staff, October 16, 1989; "Performance Appraisal Redesign for Teachers: A Report on Initial Efforts," recommended to the Superintendent of Schools and the Rochester Teachers Association President by the Career in Teaching Joint Governing Panel, September 1, 1989; memo re information bulleting, Excellence and Accountability Program, October 3; lists of districts that had not yet filed 1989-90 EIT applications as of 9/27 and 9/28/89; memos from Jim Conti to Regional Staff Directors re decisions: Jamesville-DeWitt Faculty Association v. Central School District (Denise England v. Board of Education et al.), Baylis et al. v. Board of Education of Seaford Union Free School District, Schneider et al. v. Sobol (Excellence In Teaching funds), Seaford; memo re Empire Plan Experience report for January June 1989; memo re state employee health plan costs, with attached summary report noting rise of 20 percent; memo to NYSUT local presidents of Special Act schools, August 25, 1989; administrative bulletin from New York State Teachers' Retirement System re employer contribution rate for 1990-91 school year; brochure for conference by New York State Public Sector Labor-Management Consortium, "Employee Participation in Decision Making," October 17, 1989; memos from Jim Conti re jury duty, September-October; text of legislation in the Assembly re smoking regulations, with cover memo noting that NYSUT had not taken an official position, September 8, 1989
- RSD Memos (2 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  Newspaper clippings, Bureau of National Affairs articles, and U.S. Supreme Court cases, with cover memo from Jim Conti to Regional Staff Directors, re Drug-Free Workplace Act; articles re school consolidations, HMOs, taxing of health-insurance benefits; legal memo to NYSUT general counsel Bernard Ashe re U.S. Supreme Court decision re disparate-impact claim in Wards Cove Packing Company v. Atonio, with text of opinions, June 20; article from ILR Labor Relations Review, Cornell University, "Organizing the Organizers: Professional Staff Unionism in the American Labor Movement," July 1989, text of legal suit in U.S. Court of Appeals by Ad Hoc Committee of Concerned Teachers on Behalf of Minor and Under-Age Students Attending Greenburgh Eleven Union Free School District and on its own behalf, with cover memo noting allegation of racially discriminatory employment practices, July 17; memo re EPA radon alert, May 2; memos re jury duty, September-October; analysis in Wall St. Journal of impact of Beck decision re union dues, July 13; summary of recent decisions re random drug testing, July 10; memo asking for names of districts claiming fiscal crisis situations, July 10; copy of Provocator 4/89, official publication of the Buffalo Teachers Federation (NEA), with cover memo from Jim Conti to regional staff directors, June 29; decision by Illinois Appellate Court in Decatur Board of Education et al. v. Illinois E.L.R.B. and Decatur E.A., re class size, June 26; booklets, Voluntary Labor Arbitration Rules as amended and in effect January 1, 1988, by American Arbitration Association, and Code of Professional Responsibility for Arbitrators of Labor-Management Disputes of the National Academy of Arbitrators, American Arbitration Association, and Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, as amended and in effect May 29, 1985, with cover memo, June 21; summary highlights of the anti-smoking bills passed by the state Assembly and Senate, with cover memo, June 21; Pocket Advisor: Drug Testing on the Job: Know Your Rights, with cover memo from Jim Conti, for distribution to field representatives, June 19; memos re middle-level education, with attached material from State Education Department announcing Regents Challenge for Excellence in Middle-Level Education Program, May-June; memo re rate-setting methodology for Special Act Schools and 863 Schools for 1989-90 tuition, with attached document from State Education Department, May-June; memo re Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1986, with attached overview of law and Model Driver's Manual for Commercial Vehicle Driver licensing, January 15, 1989; legal memo from NYSUT general counsel James Sander re UFT, PERB, et al. advs. NYC BOE, June 5; PERB decision CSEA et al. v. City of Auburn, April 3; memo re smoking regulations at Rush-Henrietta school district, noting that Appellate Court ruled that Commissioner's regulation supercedes PERB determination re collective bargaining, June 7; State Education Department regulations re records retention and disposition, with cover memo from Jim Conti, June 6; text of case re seniority, Christine Szumigala v. Hicksville USFD BOE, June 5; memo re Employees' Retirement System savings to local school districts, June 1; memo re availability of video, "Working in America: Hazardous Duty," shown on ABC television, May 31; confidential memos re operational policy to follow when 3020a charges are brought against a member, May 11 and 31; lists of school budget defeats, May 15 and 30; memo re interim final rules for Drug-Free Workplace requirements, May 26; related memo, May 11; memos re new local presidents' conference, May; document by Civil Service Department re cost containment strategies for public employers for health insurance programs, with cover memo, May 10; decision in state Supreme Court in Seaford, May 3; memos re Excellence in Teaching legal motions affecting distribution of monies, May 4 and March 17; letter from chairman of PERB to NYSUT president Tom Hobart re location of administrative law judge hearings under budget constraints, with cover letter from Jim Conti, May 3; NYSUT Information Bulletins re certification, tenure, and a middle school teaching assignment, and consultant teacher services, with cover memo, April 20
- RSD Memos (3 of 4), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 9)
- RSD Memos (4 of 4), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 10)
- Uniserv Unit 5A, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  Letter from chair of the 5A Coordinating Council and UNISERV liaison from Wappingers Central School Faculty Association to NYSTA headquarters, urging that a sub-office of the mid-Hudson region of unified locals be established for Poughkeepsie, June 21, 1972; 5A Council minutes of January 8 and March 4, 1972, with attached activity reports; letter from 5A chair to president of Scarsdale Teachers Association, congratulating him on unification vote, inviting him to meeting, February 28, 1972, with attached activity reports; letter from East Greenbush Teachers Association re decision to participate in formation of UNISERV 5A council, March 1, 1972; memo to UNISERV Coordinating Council noting "significant and important victory" by NYSTA-NEA over AFT/UFT in Wappingers representation election, February 4, 1972; memo to Elmsford Regional Office re Montrose contract, November 19, 1971; letters reminding locals of Coordinating Council meetings; letter urging relocation of Fishkill meeting with Al Shanker, to avoid lending credibility to visit, November 18, 1971; memo, Wappingers status report, November 18, 1971; related correspondence re Wappingers organizing efforts, October
- Uniserv Unit: Vestal 9A, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  Memo reporting meeting with local state legislators, April 7, 1972; memo re unification efforts, December 8, 1971; memos re administrative matters
- Uniserv Unit 11A, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  Staff placement form
- Uniserv Unit 11: 13 (Chuck Davies), 1972 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  Memo re staff assignment
- Uniserv Unit 12: B (Charles Rodgers), 1972 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  Memos from Buffalo Regional Office re membership potential of unified locals
- Uniserv Unit 13: A (Bill Fineman), 1972 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  Memo re Olean grievance; administrative memos
- Uniserv Corning Unit 14: A (Mr. Jack Schamel), 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  UNISERV Newspapers
- Uniserv Unit 14: A Jack Schamel (Corning), 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  Letter from Shamel to NYSTA executive secretary asking whether he could have two weeks vacation to run against Bill "Cadillac" Smith, and work part-time if elected to the state Senate, March 29, 1972; memos to Shamel critiquing regional newsletter; memos re status of Elmira Heights unification, December 1971; memo re structure, operation, and proposed budget of Corning, Elmira, Horseheads UNISERV unit, April 7, 1971
- Uniserv Utica Unit 8: A, Dan Mahoney, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  Correspondence re hiring of a non-certified teacher to fill a kindergarten position over the application of several certified teachers in the Owen D. Young Central School District, August 1972; memo to members of Coordinating Council summarizing June 15 meeting; memo from Mahoney re "rotten" settlements and fact-finding reports in Oneida County, June 1, 1972, with attached PERB fact-finder's report and recommendations for Clinton and New Hartford school districts; correspondence re arbitration hearing for retroactive pay for teachers, April-May 1972; memo to Mahoney pointing out high number of long-distance calls, directing him to limit calls to Albany office to no more than once per day, May 9, 1972; request from Mahoney for funding of $39/yr for Utica office subscription to daily newspaper to keep fully informed of local events, May 10, 1972; memo to Mahoney, suggesting that he continue to purchase Utica Daily Press on a weekly or monthly basis, May 22, 1972; memo to Mahoney directing him to curtail high clerical overtime despite need to catch up, February 28, 1972; memo to Mahoney refusing request for bookcase, citing budget constraints, May 5, 1972; repeat request from Mahoney, discussing negative effect on work of lack of basic furnishings, May 9, 1972; memo from Mahoney to Albany office, copied to Syracuse Regional Office, asking who could be contacted to obtain paper clips, noting several-week wait after request for basic office supplies, February 23, 1972; memo to Albany office re Utica office needs, noting use of cardboard boxes and orange crates as makeshift furniture, October 5, 1971; request for lease-purchase of typewriter for Utica office, December 20, 1971; list of furniture items requested by Utica office, annotated as to urgency, January 20, 1972; related correspondence
- Unification, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  Memo re request for NEA salary reimbursement for various field representatives performing work on unification campaign, November 19, 1973; memo to regional coordinators re unification contracts, guaranteed dues, March 16. 1972
- Uniserv Administration, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 21)